Simon Griffee

Communications Specialist, Visual Designer, Web Developer

Email / Facetime: simon@hypertexthero.com

Telephone: +39 333 4928016
Portfolio: hypertexthero.com

Summary

Over a decade of professional experience as communications project manager, visual designer and web developer working with small and large teams in startups and organizations. Enjoy all aspects of communications from strategic planning, content strategy and information architecture to user experience, usability, accessibility and hands-on coding and design. Capable of both developing the strategic overview of a project and also focussing on the practical details. Interested in freelance work or a position in a good communications team.

Experience

Information Exchange Officer, IPPC Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome, Italy June 2009–Present (4 years)

Promoted the International Plant Protection Convention (IPPC) brand and generated public support for its objectives. Provided design support and technical advice on the creation and evolution of websites. Identified and advised on new tools and approaches to benefit IPPC and FAO's corporate communication and advocacy goals.

- Designed and oversaw production of print materials including brochures, logotypes, letterheads and posters such as IPPC's 2011 poster: hypertexthero.com/work/international-plant-protection-convention-poster
- Designed, coded and deployed internal project management tool for implementing agile web development practices: it.ippc.int
- Wrote website HTML, CSS, JavaScript template code for www.ippc.int
 Original templates and other work can be found at: hypertexthero.com/ippc/work
- Designed, coded and deployed multi-user CMS which supports automatic user registration and document uploads using the Django web framework.
- Wrote basic Django CMS which also writes static HTML pages for the ephyto.ippc.int website.
- Designed, coded and deployed Food News website: food.hypertexthero.com

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer Hypertexthero, Worldwide 2005–Present (8 years)

Worked on a variety of web and print projects for clients around the world, from companies in London and internet start-ups in Silicon Valley to software teams involved with FAO and international schools in Rome.

- Designed business cards (eg. hypertexthero.com/work/pianist-card)
- Designed, coded and deployed plantbiosecurity.edu.au website and forum with Wordpress for the Australian Plant Biosecurity Program
- Created logotypes for IT Works: hypertexthero.com/work/it-works-logotype
 FAO Biotech: hypertexthero.com/work/food-and-agriculture-organization-biotech
- Designed and oversaw production of brochure for Mylius Yachts: hypertexthero.com/work/mylius-brochure and calendars, adverts and magazines for the American Overseas School of Rome: hypertexthero.com/work/aosr
- Wrote HTML, CSS and implemented CMS' for web startups in Palo Alto, marketing agencies in London and companies and non-profits such as confronti.net in Italy.

Designer Acotel Group S.p.A, Rome, Italy 2003–2004 (1 year)

Responsible for client-side accessible website design, mobile interface design, marketing and advertising multimedia campaigns and identity design of Acotel Group S.p.A and related companies.

- Designed, coded and deployed one of the first web standards-compliant corporate websites in Europe at the time - acotel.com
- · Designed graphics, icons and posters for mobile, web and print media

Freelance Designer European Artisans, Various, Rome, Italy 1999–2003 (4 years)

Languages

English (written & spoken - fluent)
Portuguese (written & spoken - fluent)
Italian (written and spoken - good)
French (written & spoken - basic)

Writing & Photography

I have a web and graphic design notebook at hypertexthero.com/logbook and a photographic notebook at simongriffee.com. Some highlights:

Introducing Food News: http://hypertexthero.com/logbook/2013/10/intro-food-news/ Web Design: Where to Begin: hypertexthero.com/logbook/web-design-where-to-begin

The Pareto Problem for Perfectionists: hypertexthero.com/logbook/the-pareto-problem-for-perfectionists

Don't Use Adobe Flash: hypertexthero.com/logbook/dont-use-adobe-flash

Accessible Writing on Computers: hypertexthero.com/logbook/accessible-writing-on-computers

The Internet Apprentice: hypertexthero.com/logbook/the-internet-apprentice

Me & You: simongriffee.com/story-meyou The Island: simongriffee.com/story-theisland

Skills & Expertise

Communication, Project Management, Graphic Design, Writing, Web Development, User Interface Design, Usability, Accessibility, Mobile First Design, Responsive Design, Information Architecture, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Django, Wordpress, Textpattern, Drupal, Unix, Git, Github, Apache, Nginx, MySQL, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Textmate, Terminal

Education

Stanford University · 2006

Concept Design Workshop at Stanford University's d.school

Bournemouth University · 1996–1999

BA (Hons) Creative Advertising - copywriting, art direction, marketing, digital design

Bournemouth and Poole College of Art & Design · 1997–1998

City & Guilds Diploma with Distinction in Photography

Interests

Communications, photography, web, travel, open source & open internet, philosophy, typography, art history, nature, astronomy, 'open world' computer games, music, (blues guitar, jazz, classical), vintage aeroplanes, basketball